pollstarpro.com 2019-12-19

# Pollstar | Privacy Policy

**Last Modified:**   October 1, 2018

This Privacy Policy explains how Oak View Group, LLC, OVG Media & Conferences, LLC and Pollstar, LLC (“Company,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) collects, uses, and discloses personal information.  This Privacy Policy applies to all our products, services and the Oak View Group website (http://www.oakviewgroup.com/), the Pollstar website (<https://www.pollstar.com/>), the VenuesNow website (www.venuesnow.com) and other websites or applications that may link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, “our websites”).  Where applicable, you will be informed of the identity of the data controller for your personal data when you obtain our products or services.

Where applicable, you consent to the use of your information as described in this Privacy Policy each time you visit our websites or use our products or services.

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

Personal information is information that can be used to directly or indirectly identify you.  Personal information also includes anonymous information that is linked to information that can be used to directly or indirectly identify you.  Personal information does not include information that has been irreversibly anonymized or aggregated so that it can no longer enable us, whether in combination with other information or otherwise, to identify you.

What Personal Information We Collect

We may collect different kinds of personal information from or about you:

  *          **Information you provide** :  We collect the personal information you provide—such as your name, username, address, telephone number, job title, or email address—when you use our products and services, create an account, Contact Us, register for our events and conferences, sign up through our trade show solicitations, subscribe to our newsletters online or otherwise subscribe for our notifications regarding artist, news, or conference updates, directly request to be included in our various directories, apply for employment, interact with us at in-person events, or otherwise interact with us.

  *          **Information about payments** :  If you make a purchase, we collect personal information in connection with the purchase.  This information includes payment information, such as your credit or debit card number and other card information; other account and authentication information; and billing, shipping, and contact details.

  *          **Information about use of our services and products** : When you visit our websites we may collect information about the type of device you use, your device’s unique identifier, the IP address of your device, your operating system, the type of Internet browser that you use, usage information, diagnostic information, browsing information, and location information from or about the computers, phones, or other devices on which you install or access our products or services.  We may gather some of this information automatically.

  *          **Information from third parties** : We may collect information from third parties, including business partners, marketing agencies, or publicly accessible sources.  This may include your contact information from marketing partners when we engage in joint marketing or co-branding activities, your IP address or location information from service providers to offer certain products and services relevant to your location. 

We may need to collect personal information from you by law, under a contract we have with you or in order to enter into a contract with you.  Where we need to collect personal information in such circumstances, and you fail to provide that information where you are obliged to do so or when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services).  In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

How We Use Your Personal Information

We may use personal information to provide, improve, and develop our products and services, to communicate with you, to offer you targeted advertisements and services, and to protect us and our customers.  We collect, process, and determine how to process your personal information as data controller for the following purposes:

  *          **Communicating with you** : We may communicate with you about your transactions, employment requests, or auto-notification requests regarding updates on concert and artist data, and to inform you about our policies and terms.  Such processing is based on our legitimate interest in offering you products and services and for business continuity. Subject to your prior express consent, we may use personal information to send you marketing communications in relation to our own products and services.  Also subject to your prior express consent, we may share your personal information, including your contact information listed in our directories of industry contacts, with third-party partners who may send you marketing communications in relation to their products and services.  If you no longer wish to receive email communications for marketing purposes, please Contact Us to opt out.  We may use your information to process and respond to your requests when you contact us. 

  *          **Providing, improving, and developing our products and services** :  We use personal information to help us provide, improve, and develop our products, services, and advertising, including our directories of industry contacts.  This includes using personal information for purposes such as data analysis, research, and audits. Such processing is based on our legitimate interest in offering you products and services and for business continuity.

  *          **Offering and measuring targeted advertisements and services** :  Subject to your prior express consent, we may use personal information to personalize your experience with our products and services, on third-party websites and applications, and to determine the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns. 

For any of the uses of your data described above that require your prior express consent, note that you may withdraw your consent at any time by Contacting Us.

  *          **Promoting safety and security** :  We use personal information to help verify accounts and user activity, as well as to promote safety and security, such as by monitoring fraud and investigating suspicious or potentially illegal activity or violations of our terms or policies.  Such processing is based on our legitimate interest in helping ensure the safety of our products and services.

As a global company, we have a number of corporate affiliates in different jurisdictions.  Each of these affiliates collects, processes and determines how to process your personal information as a data controller to help provide you the products and services you request.

**Cookies and Similar Technologies**

We use cookies and similar technologies (both our own and those provided by third parties) to provide, protect, and improve our products and services, such as by personalizing content, offering and measuring advertisements, understanding user behavior, and providing a safer experience. 

You can remove or reject cookies using your browser or device settings, but in some cases doing so may affect your ability to use our products and services.

Please read our Cookie Policy to learn more about how we use cookies and the choices you have.  

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

We make certain personal information available to strategic partners that work with us to provide our products and services or help us market to customers.  Personal information will only be shared by us with these companies in order to provide or improve our products, services, and advertising; it will not be shared with third parties for their own marketing purposes without your prior express consent.  We may also share personal information with corporate affiliates and in case of corporate business transfers, and for purposes of legal compliance and security.  We may also share personal information to the extent provided for in our directories as set forth below.

Service Providers

We may share personal information with companies that provide services on our behalf, such as website hosting; email services; marketing; sponsoring of promotions; auditing; payment processing; fulfilling customer orders; data analytics; providing customer support; conducting customer research and satisfaction surveys; and other services that assist in selling our products and services.  These companies are obligated to protect your information and may be located wherever we operate.

Corporate Affiliates and Corporate Business Transactions

We may share personal information with all Oak View Group-affiliated companies.  In the event of a merger, reorganization, acquisition, joint venture, assignment, spin-off, transfer, or sale or disposition of all or any portion of our business, including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings, we may transfer any and all personal information to the relevant third party. 

Directories of Industry Contacts

We disclose our directories of industry contacts, which may contain personal information, such as your name, job title, and contact information, to third parties that choose to acquire our directories. 

Legal Compliance and Security

We may disclose personal information, as necessary by law, or as a result of legal process, litigation, or requests from public or governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence.  We may also disclose personal information if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate.  We may also disclose personal information if we determine in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect our rights and pursue available remedies, enforce our terms and conditions, investigate fraud, or protect our operations or customers.

**Your Access and Control Over Information**

Depending on where you live, you may have the rights described below.  You have the right to access, correct, or delete the personal information that we collect.  You are also entitled to object, at any time, to the further processing of your personal information or restrict the purposes for which it is processed.  You have the right to receive your personal information in a structured and standard format and you have the right to have the data transferred to a third party.  You may lodge a complaint with the competent data protection authority regarding the processing of your personal information.  Please note that we can remove your contact information from a directory on request, but to the extent directory information has been transferred to any third party, you must contact such third party directly.

To protect the privacy and the security of your personal information, we may request information from you to enable us to confirm your identity and right to access such information, as well as to search for and provide you with the personal information we maintain.  There are instances where applicable laws or regulatory requirements allow or require us to refuse to provide or delete some or all of the personal information that we maintain.

You may Contact Us to exercise your rights.  We will respond to your request in a reasonable timeframe, and in any event in less than 30 days.

California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, California law permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.  To make such a request, please Contact Us and include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the request.

**Third-Party Websites and Services**

Our websites, products, and services may contain links to or the ability for you to access third-party websites, products, and services.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by those third parties, nor are we responsible for the information or content their products and services contain.  This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by us through our products and services. 

**Information Security, Integrity, and Retention**

We take reasonable technical, administrative, and physical security precautions to protect and prevent unauthorized access to your information.

It is important that you take precautions to protect against unauthorized access to your information and computers or other devices.  If you feel that the security of your personal information has been compromised in connection with our products or services, please immediately Contact Us. Please be aware that, despite our efforts, no security system is impenetrable.  In the event of a security breach, we will promptly notify you and the proper authorities if required by law.

We will retain your personal information for as long as it is necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

**Children**

We do not knowingly collect, use, or disclose information from children under 16.  If we learn that we have collected the personal information of a child under 16—or the equivalent minimum age depending on the jurisdiction, such as 13 in the United States—we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.  Please immediately Contact Us. If you become aware that a child under 16 has provided us with personal information.

**Information Transfers, Storage, and Processing Globally**

If applicable, when we share your personal information with our partners, affiliates, and service providers, your personal information may be transferred to and/or made accessible from countries out of the European Economic Area (“EEA”).  In such circumstances, we will enter into model contractual clauses as adopted by the European Commission, or rely on alternative legal bases such as the Privacy Shield, where applicable, or binding corporate rules where our partners or service providers have adopted such internal policies approved by European data protection authorities.  If you reside in the EEA and would like to obtain a copy of the safeguards used to transfer your data out of the EEA, you can Contact Us with your request.

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**

We may periodically change this Privacy Policy and expect most changes to be minor.  Any non-material changes will take effect immediately upon posting of an updated Privacy Policy.  For any significant changes to the Privacy Policy, we will provide you with a prominent notice of such changes.

Your continued use of our products and services after the effective date of this Privacy Policy means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree to the revised Privacy Policy, please refrain from using our products or services. 

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, you may contact us at Oak View Group, 1100 Glendon Ave., 21st Floor, Los Angeles CA 90024, Attn: Legal Department / Privacy Policy.
